Mahmoud Refaat

An experienced Android developer, I have studied Android native for over a year using Java and Kotlin. Additionally, I have studied flutter for three months and have created several test projects on Github to further develop my skills. I have experience as an android development instructor.

EXPERIENCE

Potensia systems, Nasr City ,cairo — *Light Current Engineer*

Apr 2022- May 2023

- Planning and Implementing of The Low current systems (CCTV, Fingerprint, WIFI, and structure cabling) Directing, Instructing and supervising Installation & Maintenance Teams.
- <u>Thanks letter</u>, From parrotel aquapark hotels for the installed CCTV and WIFI systems .

Tree, student Activity At cairo university — Android Development Instructor

Oct 2018- oct 2019

- Instructor for more than 20 CS students.
- Develop and deliver effective presentations and sessions to help students learn and achieve their goals.
- Provide feedback and assessments.
- I was rewarded as a **Best Trainer** of the year .

ACM, Student Activity At Thebes Academy— Contestant

July 2018 - june 2019

- participated in The 2018 Thebes academy and El Shorouk Academy collegiate programming contest .
- ACM Twenty First PlaceContestant .

SKILLS

Kotlin, Android, Java, Xml ,Rest Api,Retrofit,architecture patterns, MVVM, MVP, Firebase,Rx java ,Flutter, Git & Github,C++, SQlite, MYSQL, CCNA ,photoshop, problem solving , Project management , Scheduling, Flexibility ,Time management , Self-motivation, Analytical thinking .

PROJECTS

Workify — <u>Available on Github</u>

Android application with java and xml that you can easily book a room from co-working space - FrontEnd .

JSON Parsing in Android using Volley — <u>Available on Github</u>

This is a java example for JSON Parsing in Android using Volley with fake json data.

Helwan, Cairo
Egypt
(+2)01211952062
Military Status: Completed
Marital Status: Single
mahhmoudrefat@outlook.com
Linkedin github

EDUCATION

Thebes Academy, Maadi—bachelor of computer science

OCT 2016- JUN 2020 Overall degree : - Very good .

COURSES

Rx Java & REST APIs , coding with nerds, Online -Jun 2023 .

Android development with kotlin, Philipp Lackner, Online -May 2023

Kotlin basics , Philipp Lackner , Online -May 2023 .

Flutter & Dart Complete
Development Course, Tharwat
Samy, udemy-Mar 2022.

Android development by Java ,Prabeesh , online - Mar 2019.

Android development ,Pixels Egypt - Aug 2018 .

Java SE course <u>,**Mahara tech**</u> -Jun 2019 .

Java SE , Appsstuff Solutions , online - Sep 2018.

CCNA 200-301, online -Oct 2022.

UI/UX Design With Adobe XD Udemy -Sep 2018 .

LANGUAGES

English - very good

American Sign Language Translator — <u>Graduation project</u>

GPA: Excellent

Android application with java and machine learning used to capture the gesture of hand by mobile camera and interprets these captures into readable text .

Day Organizer — <u>Available on Github</u>

Flutter App that organizes Your day by making a list of your day tasks. By using sqlite and Bloc state management.

HR system— Available on Github

In pure Php, HTML, CSS, and js (no frameworks). A simple web application to manage people in a company for the web development school subject..

Payroll System — <u>Available on Github</u>

C++ desktop applications calculate the salary for the employee.

Fingerprint System — Banisuef El Gadida City Authority.

It is a City Authority building at Banisuef El Gadida City . We made a Fingerprint System consisting of 8 Fingerprint devices .

WIFI and CCTV System — Parrotel Aquapark Resorts.

It is a hotel at Sharm el-sheikh. We made a wifi system of 350 Access points and CCTV system with a number of 170 Cameras.

VOLUNTEERING

AYB, Student Activity At AinShams— Tutor

Sep 2018 - May 2019

• a Tutor at AYB believing that we should strive to reduce illiteracy.

ACM, Student Activity At Thebes Academy — Graphic design

July 2018 - june 2019

- Member of the social media team.
- Design id ,social media posts .

MUS, Student Activity At cairo university— Head of Design Committee

Sep 2017- sep 2018

- Design Committee team leader.
- Designed id, certificates, social media posts, flayer, banner